David A. Yetman papers, 1957-1990
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
David A. Yetman papers, 1957-1990
MS 382
Yetman, David, 1941-
This collection contains materials that primarily concern Yetman's terms as a member of the Pima County Board of Supervisors in the late 1970's and early 1980's. Mostly comprised of newspaper clippings, the collection also includes correspondence, speeches, campaign materials, photographs, and certificates.
.5 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
David A. Yetman obtained his Ph.D. in Philosophy from the University of Arizona. He later went on to work as a professor for the university and as an associate research scientist for the University of Arizona Southwest Studies Center. He was also elected to three terms as a member of the Pima County Board of Supervisors and served as executive director of the Tucson Audubon Society. David Yetman's career has also expanded into the realm of television, as host of The Desert Speaks, a local Tucson PBS program on KUAT.
Dr. Yetman is also an accomplished author and photographer. His books include: Where the Desert Meets the Sea: A Trader in the Land of the Seri Indians; Sonora: An Intimate Geography; Gentry's Rio Mayo Plants: the Tropical Deciduous Forest and Environs of Northwest Mexico; Scattered Round Stones: A Mayo Village in Sonora, Mexico; Mayo Ethnobotany: Land History, and Traditional Knowledge in Northwest Mexico; and Hidden People: The Guarijíos of Northwest Mexico and their Ethnobotany
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains materials that primarily concern Yetman's terms as a member of the Pima County Board of Supervisors in the late 1970's and early 1980's. The majority of the collection is comprised of newspaper clippings, which include Yetman or the Pima County Board of Supervisors. This collection also contains correspondence, speeches, campaign materials, photographs, and certificates.
Access Terms
Yetman, David, 1941-
Yetman, David, 1941- -- Correspondence.
Yetman, David, 1941- -- Speeches.
Yetman, David, 1941- -- Photographs.
Yetman, David, 1941- -- Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.).
Moore, Ed.
Joyner, Conrad.
Pima County (Ariz.) -- Politics and government.
Tucson, Arizona.
Container List
- Correspondence, 1964-1988 No date (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Speeches, 1977-1987 No date (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Campaign materials, 1980 No date (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Materials regarding Ed Moore, 1986-1987 No date (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Materials regarding Joyner bribery allegations and investigation, 1982-1983 No date (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Photographs of Yetman and unidentified individuals, No date (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Certificates 1976-1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- David Yetman Trail Dedication, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Newspaper clippings regarding Yetman, 1957-1960 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Newspaper clippings regarding Yetman, 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Newspaper clippings regarding Yetman, 1980-1985 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Newspaper clippings regarding Yetman, 1980-1985 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Newspaper clippings regarding Pima County Board of Supervisors, 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Newspaper clippings regarding Yetman, No Date (Box 1, Folder 14)